地球百子  前情提要
previously on "the 100"...
- 他们是谋杀犯  - 鼓动人们
- they're murderers - raising people
放弃自己的身体
to give up their bodies.
我们可以等宝贝女儿56年
we can wait 56 years for our baby girl,
也可以今晚就带她回来
or we can get her back tonight.
宿主的思想已被抹除  大脑完好无损
the mind of the host is erased. the brain is left unharmed.
- 爸爸  - 是我
- Dad - yeah
地球上的人  他们中有多少是宿主
the people from earth, how many of them are hosts
我们不清楚
we don't know.
这就是你要去调查的
that's what you're going to find out.
艾寇在实验室将自己变成了夜之血脉
echo made herself a nightblood in the lab,
和艾比转化克拉克的方式一样
same way abby did to clarke.
多少人进行了血液变更
how many people have blood alteration
告诉我  我想知道的  我再扔给你们绳子
pass us the rope, and we'll tell you what you want to know.
- 这他妈是什么声音  - 瞬时风暴
- what the hell is that - a temporal flare.
快点  他就要逃走了
come on. he's getting away.
在我的梦里  我看见一个很吓人的指挥官
in my dreams, i see a commander who frightens me.
是暗黑指挥官
sheidheda, the dark commander.
所以我们才要一直训练啊
that's why we must keep training.
你是谁
who are you
约瑟芬  光明之子  幸会
josephine lightborne. nice to meet you.
他们是不是说服你说  我们应该离开天堂
have they convinced you that we should leave paradise
我为什么要离开我的家呢
why would i leave my home
你不是克拉克
you're not clarke.
你想得到永生吗
how would you like  to be immortal, too
所以克拉克不是指挥官
so clarke was a commander.
是的  我和你说过
no. i told you,
她当时还不是夜之血脉
she wasn't a nightblood then.
艾比让我用手按压安塔利的心脏
abby made me pump ontari's heart
这样她的大脑就不会融化
with my bare hands so her brain wouldn't melt,
感觉有点恶心
kind of gross.
如果让我做的话  我还会觉得挺厉害的呢
hmm, kind of badass if you ask me.
我没做  不过谢谢夸奖
i didn't, but thank you.
嘿  我给你的条件可是永生
hey, i am offering you immortality,
踏上神坛的机会
a chance at godhood,
你却连眼睛都不睁开
and you can't  keep your eyes open
即使是神也需要睡觉啊
yeah. well, even gods need to sleep.
对了  你怎么不要睡觉
why don't you, by the way
在新宿主身体里的头几天
sleeplessness is common
失眠是正常现象
the first few nights in a new host.
你死后可以接着睡
you can sleep when you're dead,
但如果你改变主意了  就永远不会醒来了
which will be never unless you've changed your mind.
- 我还没改主意  - 很好
- i haven't. - good.
现在清醒一下  然后告诉我怎么能装的更像克拉克
now wake up and show me how to be clarke enough
来骗过她妈
to fool her mother because
没有夜之血脉  就没有启动器
no nightblood, no drives.
- 好吧  - 那就来演练一下
- fine. - lightning round.
当艾比趾高气昂的时候  你该怎么办
what card do you play when abby's on her high horse
说说黑暗年代  同类相食的年代
the dark year, cannibalism. yum.
当你要让她感到羞愧的时候呢
when you want to sprinkle on some shame
- 说说她上瘾的事 - 很妙
- addiction. - inspiration
克拉克在气象山的时候
uh, clarke in mount weather,
克拉克在光明之城的时候
clarke in the city of light,
克拉克留下来
clarke staying behind so that you guys
顺便说一句  她还挺酷的
could go to space, which was fairly awesome, by the way.
没错  除非你挡了她的路
yeah, unless you got in her way.
不错  你已经上道了
ok. you've softened the ground.
克拉克快被你攻破了  来个终结技
she's ready to break. take the kill shot.
我父亲  以叛逃罪被处决
daddy--executed for treason
罪行是被艾比揭露的
and turned in by abby herself.
不错  没准你真能蒙混过关
not bad. maybe you do pull this off.
那应该是玛蒂的声音  你的孩子  你知道的
that would be madi-- oh, you know, your kid.
去看看吧  就当排练了
consider it a dress rehearsal.
好吧
fine.
噢  小心点  杀手先生
oh, uh-uh-uh. easy, killer.
首先  你先帮我过了艾比这关
first, you get me past abby,
然后我再解决我的朋友们
and then i wipe my friends.
不  不  不
no, no, no.
在她和指挥官交流的时候你不能打断她
you don't interrupt her when she's communing
暗黑指挥官
with the commanders, not even sheidheda, the dark commander.
眼泪是救不了你的
今夜我将饮你鲜血
他的力量越来越强了
he's getting too strong.
所以我们现在必须要进行分离仪式了
that's why we have to do the separation ritual now.
我是不会让她遭罪的  玛蒂  醒醒
i'm not letting her suffer. madi, wake up.
嘿  醒醒
hey, wake up.
克拉克
clarke
是我  我在这里
yep. that's right. i'm here.
你只是做了个噩梦
it was just a nightmare, ok
不  那是一段记忆
no. it was a memory.
- 那不是真的  - 你知道那不是真的
- it wasn't real. - you know that's not true.
对她来说真实无比  你这样打断她
it is real for her, and ripping her out
可能会对她造成永久性的伤害
can permanently damage her.
现在不是好好的吗  是吧  玛蒂
but it didn't, did it, madi
你不知道刚刚那样做会对她的思想
you don't know what that just did
或者是火焰产生什么影响
to her mind or to the flame.
我还好  只是感觉很累
i'm fine, ok i'm just tired.
休息一下吧  我们该走了
get some rest. we should go.
是啊  说的对  你确实该走了
yeah. you're right. you should.
你们两个都出去
both of you.
闭嘴  我们重新开始
shut up. let's start again.
地 球 百 子
第六季        第六集
翻译： cecilia  lysenko
翻译： 噬魂
翻译：  rossygeng
翻译： 岛岛
校对： 噬魂
时间轴/特效：小螺号
统筹：Kate
总监：麦斯
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
艾寇  埃默里  瑞文
echo, emori, raven.
- 嘿  - 那不是我
- hey. - it wasn't me.
清醒下  表演时间到了
pull it together. show time.
家庭会议
family meeting.
贝拉米呢
where's bellamy
- 怎么了  发生什么了吗  - 我们碰到乔丹了
- why what's wrong - we ran into jordan.
他们是永生的  是真的吗
is it true they're immortal
他说的应该比实际情况更糟糕
i'm sure he made it sound worse than it really is.
他们是杀人犯  抢劫身体的罪犯
they're murderers and body snatchers.
我们离开这里又会比这糟糕多少
how much worse could it be we're out of here.
嘿  嘿  冷静一下  我们要去哪里
hey, hey, slow down. where are we gonna go
墨菲说得对  按原计划不变
murphy's right. the plan doesn't change.
我们留在这里  从他们那里学到尽可能多的东西
we stay and learn as much from them as we can
我们就可以修建自己的生存之地了
so we can build our own compound.
这会贝拉米在外面寻找合适的地点
bellamy's out scouting a location as we speak.
他没带我一起去
he went without me
偷盗身体这件事点起了小火苗
this whole body-snatching thing just really lit a fire.
他和一个觅食小队一起出去了
he's out with a foraging party.
你们当时还和赖克在一起
you guys were still with ryker.
你让他自己去了
you let him go alone
等一等  克拉克
wait a second. back up, clarke.
你是希望我们还继续装好人吗
you expect us to continue to play nice
我们的确还需要赖克
we do still need ryker to tell us
来告诉我们怎么弄辐射屏障
how to bend the radiation field.
不用了  我自己能搞定
no. i'll figure it out myself.
瑞文  我知道这很难
raven, i know this is hard,
为了生存
but we've all done things that we're not proud of to survive.
我没有做过
i haven't.
好吧  我会试试的
fine. i'll try.
我和她一起去
i'll go with her,
确保她别挑起一场战争来
make sure she doesn't start a war.
我去找贝拉米
i'm going after bellamy.
艾寇将会是个麻烦
echo's going to be a problem.
我会派人盯着点她
i'll send jade to keep an eye on her.
说到贝拉米
yeah. back to bellamy,
根本没有什么觅食小队吧
there's no foraging party, is there
当然有了  每天早上都有
sure, there is, every morning.
只不过他不在队里而已
he's just not on it.
他发现我不是克拉克
he found out that i wasn't clarke.
对天发誓  要是你杀了他
swear to god, if you killed him--
我没有  但如果必要的话  我会
i didn't, but i will if i have to.
你不明白
you don't get it.
要是贝拉米知道克拉克死了
if bellamy knows that clarke is dead,
那这一切都是徒劳的
then all of this is for nothing.
他现在说不定就在自杀
he may was well just kill himself now.
那似乎是有点冲动了
that seems a tad impulsive.
我之前想等到第二月
i was thinking of giving it till second moon.
当觅食队伍回来的时候
that's when the foraging party comes back
艾寇就会发现我在说谎
and echo finds out i was lying.
在那之前  你必须
you have until then to get him
让他站到天使一边
on the side of the angels.
我们就是天使
the angels being us
约翰  我们都是自己故事里的英雄
we're all the hero of our own story, john.
来吧  我带你去见他
come on. i'll take you to him.
跟着艾寇
follow echo.
放我走
uh! let me go!
你们干什么
what the hell are you doing uh!
放我出去
let me out!
墨菲
murphy.
贝拉米
bellamy.
你也想明白了
heh. oh, you figured it out, too, huh
我打赌  我能做出个什么割断这绳子
i bet that i can make something to cut this strap.
- 还有谁知道  - 没别人  只有我们
- who else knows  - nobody yet. just us.
他们想要和我交易
tried to offer me a deal.
什么交易
what deal
我们答应不报复
we agree not to retaliate,
他们就帮我们建立营地
they help us build our compound.
你怎么说
and what did you say
你觉得我会怎么说
what do you think i said
那是克拉克
it's clarke.
我也许不怎么喜欢她
she might not have been my favorite of late.
但她仍是我们中一员
she's still one of ours.
她很关心你  墨菲
she cared about you, murphy.
我知道也许有时候你们
i know that it may not have always
有些误会  但她确实是这样的
seemed like it, but she did.
她关心我们所有人
she cared about all of us,
她绝不会让我们死在这
and she would never let us die here.
你是说我们应该接受交易
you saying we should take the deal
不  不  你说得对
no. no. you were right.
我们不需要他们帮忙建立我们自己的营地
we don't need them to help us build our own compound.
我们杀光他们  占据他们的就行
we kill them all, and we take theirs.
你需要她的时候  血腥女王在哪
where's blodreina when you need her
生物荧光  酷
bioluminescence. cool.
如果这是另一个陷阱呢
what if it's another trap
你不会给死人设陷阱的
you don't trap something you think is already dead.
安静  跟着我
quiet. on me.
别动  别逼我开枪
don't move. don't make me shoot you.
放下
drop it.
奥克塔维亚  你怎么了  走
octavia, what is it what's wrong move.
- 被辐射了  - 在扩散
- fascinating. - oh, it's spreading.
- 这是什么  - 我假设她沉到沼泽里
- what is this - i assume she went under,
仅剩下一只手暴露在瞬时风暴里
leaving only her hand exposed to temporal flare,
还好不是全部  否则它会像树木一样变成化石
though not fully, or it'd be fossilized like the trees.
我能帮她
i can help her,
但不是在枪口下
not at the point of a gun.
明智的选择
good choice.
有药物能治疗  不过要得到它
there's medicine, but to get it,
我们需要回到它发生的地方
we need to go back to the place where it happened.
在扩散到她的大脑
i'll give her 3 hours tops.
并要了她性命之前
before the time dilation reaches her brain
她最多只有3小时
and she's dead.
见那个老人  否则就杀了你
fine, but then you're taking me to the old man, or you're dead.
你是在找加百列
ah, so you're looking for gabriel.
拉塞尔承诺了你什么
what did russell promise you
40个处女加一碟小菜
40 vestal virgins and a side dish
无论是什么  和你无关
of none of your damn business.
我保证  你不会无聊的
you're not boring. i give you that.
相位变化的空间光调制器
channel the radiation through a spatial light modulator
来引导辐射
with a calculated phase variation.
然后辐射就在自由空间中沿曲线运动
and it follows a curved trajectory in free space.
酷  明白了
cool. got it.
我们临时安装了
we jury-rig the security pylons
埃利吉乌斯用来为囚犯
eligius used for the prisoners
- 处理辐射的安全塔  - 我们提供燃料反应堆
- to handle the radiation. - we provide the reactor fuel.
我相信  你们是出于好心
yeah, out of the goodness of your own hearts, i'm sure.
我有错过什么吗
did i miss something
不  是我错过了
no. i did.
我想是时候休息下了
i think it's time to get some rest.
你们知道多久了
how long have you known
不用  你去吧  我不需要休息
no. you go. i don't need rest.
我要尽快搞定这个
i need to get this done as fast as i can
这样我们就能离开这了
so we can get the hell out of here.
作为一个长期忍受痛苦
you know, as someone who's lived with pain
久到我已经记不清的人
for longer than i can remember,
我也想要一个新的身体
i can get wanting a new body,
只是不会杀掉其他人
just wouldn't murder someone else for it.
这不是谋杀  我们不会强迫别人
it's not murder. we don't force people.
没错  我差点忘了
oh, yeah. that's right. i forgot.
你让他们从出生起就相信你们是神
you raise them from birth to believe you're gods
这样他们就会为了大我
so they sacrifice themselves willingly
而甘愿牺牲自己
for the greater glory of you.
被崇敬的感觉一定很不错
it must be nice to be worshipped.
其实不是
no, not really.
这是你和你妈
this you and your mom
普丽娅  愿人们尊她的名为圣
priya, right hallowed be her name.
- 没错  - 怎么了
- yeah. - what's wrong
我确定她要比某些酒吧侍女更重要
i'm sure she's way more important than some barmaid.
当然  黛利拉不只是一个酒吧侍女
of course, delilah wasn't just a barmaid, was she
她还是一个女儿  一个朋友
she was a daughter and a friend.
我当时还是个小孩
i was just a kid.
在这照片拍了没多久
russell killed us in the first red sun
拉塞尔就在第一个红日的时候杀了我们
not long after this was taken.
我没要求他们复活我
i didn't ask to be resurrected.
是没有  不过你现在
no, but you're
已经是第九次转世了  对吧
ryker the ninth now, though, right,
有八个身体
8 bodies
你夺舍这具身体的时候多大了
how old were you when you snatched this one
206岁
206.
我现在去看看反应堆
i'll look at that reactor now.
伙计们  我们单子上的第一位
guys, number one on our list--
埃利吉乌斯仪式的红日蘑菇
red sun mushroom eligius protocol.
约瑟芬·普莱姆最喜欢的仪式
oh, josephine prime's favorite ritual,
这就是我想她的原因
reason i miss her.
恭敬一点  我们还在贡品林里
be respectful. we're still in the offering grove.
谁会不带地图就去侦查
who leaves to scout without a map
杀了我
mercy.
我救你出来
i'll get you out of here.
请杀了我  他们在我的身体里
please. mercy. they're inside me.
住手  不要
stop! uh! no.
你之前在酒馆里  你为什么要跟踪我
you were in the tavern. why are you following me
我有我的命令  走吧
i have my orders. let's go.
他很痛苦
he's in pain.
不关你的事
not that it's any of your business,
这是他选的路
but he chose this path.
杰德
jade...
你很强大  你可以的
you're strong. you can do this.
和我一起
join me.
我很想  朋友
i would, my friend,
但我还有别的任务
but i have another charge.
你认识他
you know him
他就是萝丝被抓那晚
he's the guard who lowered the shield
放下辐射护盾让你们船进入的那个守卫
that let your ship in the night they took rose.
他责怪自己害死了她
he blames himself for her death.
他该怨我的
he should blame me.
快走吧
now let's go.
- 仁慈  - 我说了不要
- mercy. - i said no! uh!
你的战斗结束了
省点力气  会用得上的
hey, save your energy. you're gonna need it.
留着干嘛  又要打仗吗
yeah for what, another war
这真的是克拉克想要的吗
is that really what clarke would want
我不知道克拉克想要什么
i don't know what clarke would want.
可惜我们不能问她了
it's too bad we can't ask her.
我们都知道她想要做得更好
we know she wanted to do better.
无论如何我认为  为了复仇
somehow i don't think risking all of our lives
置所有人性命于不顾  并非是明智之举
for revenge is a step in the right direction.
你为何没像我一样被拘禁
why aren't you restrained like me
不清楚
i don't know.
也许我看上去不太能砍下他们的头
maybe i seem less likely to rip their heads off.
你到底来这干嘛的  墨菲
why are you really here, murphy
你真想知道吗
you really want to know
- 是啊  - 好吧
- yeah. - fine.
我来这说服你接受条件
i'm here to convince you to take the deal.
就这样  说完了
there. i said it.
为何我毫不惊讶
why am i not surprised
你死的时候看到什么了  墨菲
what did you see when you died, murphy
我在拼死保命吗
am i trying to save my own ass
对  没错  但我也
yeah. i am, but i'm also
救了你的命  就像红日时那样
saving yours, just like i did during the red sun.
贝拉米  如果我们接受了条件
bellamy, if we take this deal,
就能得到一切想要的东西
we get everything we want.
我们就能活
we get to live.
克拉克不能
not clarke.
我们无法带她回去
we can't bring her back.
我们无法保证其余人也能不死
we can make sure the rest of us survive,
从你开始
starting with you.
如果你不接受
if you don't take this deal,
约瑟芬会杀了你
josephine will kill you.
- 那就让她试试  - 那就这样
- then let her try. - oh, so that's it, then
我们再开始一场大战  再毁掉一个星球
we start another war we destroy another planet
这是蒙蒂想看到的吗
is that what you want is that what monty would have wanted
蒙蒂  听我说
hey, monty-- listen to me.
蒙蒂会以你为耻的
monty would be ashamed of you.
或许吧
maybe he would be,
或许他会看到有更好的解决方式
or maybe he'd see that this is how we do better.
滚
huh. get out.
别担心
don't worry.
我会尽我所能保证他们只杀你
i'll do my best to make sure they only kill you.
等等  你看我说的对不对
wait. tell me if i got this right.
那个老人是加百列的始祖
the old man is actually the original gabriel,
所以就成了恐怖分子
prime number 13, only he lost his stomach for immortality, so he became a terrorist
杀自己人
to kill his own people.
他管这叫道德觉醒
he'd call it a moral awakening.
我们不都这样
don't we all
你是在找救赎
so you're looking for redemption--
是吗
is that it--
帮拉塞尔杀加百列
by helping russell kill gabriel.
我可以告诉你个更好的办法
i can offer you a better way.
不用  去他妈救赎
no. screw redemption.
我懂了
ah, i see.
这孩子会被视作毫无价值
heh. did russell tell you the child will be considered worthless
因你没有血统  所以她也不会有
you don't have the blood, and neither will she.
他们会称她为零
they'll call her a null.
她不能生儿育女
she won't be able to bear children.
她会去刷厕所  或者以守卫的身份
she'll clean toilets or volunteer to die
自愿赴死或者陪葬
as a guard or attend to the dead.
- 至少她能活着  - 如果你称这为活着的话
- at least she'll be alive. - if you could call it that.
别废话了
save your breath.
我是不会加入你们叛军的
i'm not joining your little rebellion.
我为失败的事业而奋起反抗的日子已经结束了
my days of fighting for lost causes are over.
真的吗
really
那解释一下奥克塔维亚吧
then explain octavia.
她就像他们来时一样迷茫  你还帮她
she's as lost as they come, yet you help her.
慢点
easy.
知道我怎么看吗
you know what i think
我看你不想
i think you don't want her to end up
让她重蹈你的覆辙
on the same page of your history books as you.
你知道的不少
you see a lot.
这怎么可能
how is this possible
这个问题要问那个老人
that's a question for the old man.
也许在你杀他之前他会告诉你
maybe he'll answer it before you kill him.
有了
here it comes.
树液是你的神奇解药
tree sap that's your miracle cure
如果你是在拖延时间
so help me god, if you're just buying time
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
等你的朋友来救你的话
for your friends to come and save you--
拖延时间
"buying time."
这词用得好
interesting choice of words.
我还是更喜欢瓶子里的时间
i prefer time in a bottle.
放开我
aah! leave me alone!
指挥官
heda.
我在镜子里看到了他们
i see them in mirrors.
马上他们就会遍布这里
soon, they'll be everywhere.
所以我们才要立刻进行分离仪式
that's why we need to do the separation ritual now.
克拉克呢
where's clarke
我们没时间再等了  指挥官
i don't think we have time to wait anymore, heda.
你必须要自己坚强点
you'll have to be strong without her.
我从来没这样过
now, i've never done this before,
但幸运的是  瑞文还留着提图斯的书
but, luckily, raven kept titus' book.
里面有贝卡首席指挥官的智慧
it contains the wisdom of bekka pramheda.
仪式很简单
the ritual is simple,
但你必须前所未有的专注
but you'll need to focus like never before.
你不是独身一人
you won't be alone.
根据这上面说的  火焰中有个幻梦空间
according to this, there's a dream space
在那里你可以召唤
in the flame where you can summon
其他指挥官来对抗暗黑指挥官
the other commanders to confront sheidheda,
但如果出什么问题的话  你需要抓住
but if anything goes wrong, you need to hold on
美好的记忆  把它当做盾牌一般
to a good memory, let it be like a shelter
让你在风暴中平安无事
that keeps you safe in a storm.
你有这样的记忆吗
do you have that memory
我遇见克拉克的那天
the day i met clarke,
就在捕熊陷阱前面
before the bear trap.
太好了
perfect.
身体靠后  闭眼
now lean back. close your eyes.
集中精力  重复我的话
concentrate and repeat after me.
火焰指引着我  而我即是火焰
火焰指引着我
而我即是火焰
其他指挥官呢
现在  只有你
和我
你的老师
一无所知
我的老师也是
他试图挽回我
她惧怕你的能力
她想控制你
我的第一任老师想控制我
所以不顾一切的让我遵从他
他把我拴上锁链
所以我杀了他
你必须
杀了她
在她杀你之前  因为她必将行此事
不  你骗人
no. you're a liar.
火焰指引着我
而我即火焰
指挥官
heda
怎么回事  放开我
what is this let me go.
还没完呢  仪式还要重复
we're not through. the ritual takes repetition.
锁你是为了保护你防止他闯入
the restraint is to protect you in case he breaks through.
咱们再试一次
let's start again.
克拉克知道这些吗
does clarke know about this
克拉克不在  坐下吧
clarke's not here. now sit down.
健全的精神  健全的身体  健全的心灵
sound mind, sound body, sound heart.
都被普莱姆所守护
blessed be the primes.
凯恩的麻烦有进展了吗
any progress on the kane problem
凯恩的麻烦
"the kane problem"
你是这么觉得的吗
is that what you think this is
没  还没进展
no. no. there's no progress.
我不是那个意思
that's not what i meant.
普莱姆有办法拯救凯恩
what if i told you the primes had a way to save kane...
但为了达成
but to do it,
你得先把他变成一个夜之血脉
you'd have to turn him into a nightblood first
你在说什么
what are you talking about
进来  我给你看
come inside, and i'll show you.
这个被称为圣所之奇迹
they call it the miracle of sanctum.
你只需要
all you need to do
教他们如何做出夜血
is teach them how to make nightblood,
然后就是你的了  我意思是凯恩的
and then that's yours-- well, kane's, i mean.
你让他成为夜之血脉  然后你下载他的思想
you make him a nightblood, you download his mind.
就这样  真的是奇迹
that's it. it really is a miracle.
他的思想会进入另一个人的身体
his mind is gonna go in another person's body
但我们做过更坏的事情啊  不是吗
but we've done worse, haven't we--
方舟上逼人自杀
the culling on the ark,
气象山事件  贝卡的实验室
mount weather, becca's lab.
我们那样是为了生存  为了所有人生存
no. we did that to survive, for all of us to survive.
我们做到了  我们活下来了
and we did. we survived.
现在  该找回人性了
now we get our humanity back.
通过夺走无辜的性命吗
by taking innocent lives
会自愿帮忙的
russell told me that his people would volunteer for this.
如果普莱姆可以制造夜血
if the primes can make nightblood,
那就可以一次把他们都带回来
then they can bring back all of them at once.
这将会是这里所发生的
it would be the most spectacular thing
最不可思议的事情
that's ever happened here,
人们会因此爱戴你的
and people would love you for it.
这听着不像你说的话  克拉克
that doesn't sound like you, clarke.
我知道
i know.
只是
i know. it's just...
凯恩应该在这的  妈
kane should be here, mom,
比我们其他人加起来都应该
more than the rest of us combined.
我们都想要做好人
we've been trying to be the good guys,
但他真的就是好人
but he's just good.
是啊
yeah.
他是
yes. he is.
而且这件事不止关乎于你
and this isn't just about you.
我们此刻无比的需要他
we need him more than ever.
如果他能在波利斯达成和平
if he could negotiate peace in polis,
那他就可以立刻拯救我们了
then he can save us here and now.
我们需要拯救吗
i wasn't aware that we needed saving.
不需要
we don't.
就是一种表达方式
it's just a figure of speech.
听我说
listen to me.
妈妈
mom,
我知道爸爸的死  你怪自己
i know you blame yourself for dad's death...
我也知道凯恩的事情
and i know you blame your addiction
你怪自己的成瘾问题
for what happened to kane.
妈妈  我很担心如果我们再失去他
mom, i'm afraid of what will happen to you
你会发生什么
if we lose him, too.
我不能失去你
i can't lose you.
好  我会做的
ok. i'll do it.
利家已经作为我们普莱姆家族的人
the lees have been  part of our prime family
超过200年了
for over 200 years.
我们怎么能就这么彻底把他们清除呢
how can we just erase them forever
我们也没得选啊
we don't really have a choice.
我的任务已经完成了
i've done my job.
艾比会教我们如何做出夜血
abby will show us how to make nightblood,
但前提是我们带回她的爱人
but only if we bring her lover back.
为什么来找我  而不是你父亲
why come to me,  and not your father
我爸认为对于这颗心来说
dad thinks with is heart--
这个身体就是证明
this body is proof of that--
但我们得实际点啊
but we have to be practical.
我们没寄主了
we have zero hosts,
要么就死在这些躯体之内
so we either die in these bodies
要么抹除李一家  然后永生
or we wipe the lees and live forever.
妈妈  一旦等艾比教你如何制造夜血
mom, once abby shows you how to make nightblood,
我们就永远不会死了
we'll never be on ice again.
最好的部分就是  不再有零  不再有奉献
the best part-- no more nulls, no oblation.
任何人都可以当寄主
anyone can be a host.
我们可以随意选择遗传基因
we'll have the genetic pick of the litter.
感谢你们的牺牲
thank you for your sacrifice.
能把这个关了吗
mind turning that off
别动那个
hey, don't touch that.
我在工作  关掉
i'm trying to work. turn it off.
这是我第二任寄主做的  阿莱霍
my second host built that, alejo,
12岁的时候  用旧收音机做的
made it when he was 12 out of recycled radios.
至少他们还是有点用处的
at least they were still good for something, huh
作为献给诸神的祭品吧
an offering to the gods, huh
你怎么能这样
how do you do that
你怎么能把很美的东西  形容成很亵渎的感觉呢
how do you make something beautiful seem so profane
告诉你一下啊  保留着一个
news flash-- keeping a gift
被你偷了身体的人做的礼物
from somebody  whose body you stole
本身就是亵渎
is profane.
那这个呢
how about this
这是我第六个寄主给我的
this was given to my sixth host,
泰曼·艾弗里  他母亲安娜贝尔寄来的
tyman averi, from his mother annabel.
每个月  我们都一起庆祝泰的生命
every month, we celebrate ty's life together.
这也是一种亵渎吗
is that profane
所以你还没忘记那些为你死去的人们啊
so you haven't forgotten     the people who died for you.
- 好感动哦  - 我每天都在想他们
- i'm touched. - i think about them every day.
嘿  艾比找你
hey, abbi needs you.
干什么
what for
不知道  凯恩的事情吧
i don't know, something about kane.
她要你赶快去母船
she needs to get up to the mothership asap.
那不打扰你了
i'll relieve you here.
飞行愉快
have a nice flight.
我能问你个问题呢
hey, can i ask you a question
这是你最后一个身体吗
is this your last body
嗯  我想也是
yeah. didn't think so.
我去了我们选择作为居住地的地方
went to the spot we chose for our settlement.
贝拉米不在那里
bellamy wasn't there.
你已经知道了
you already know that.
他在哪
where is he
请解开我
please. cut me loose.
这些蔓藤  我能感觉到他们侵入了我的皮肤
the vines, i can feel them under my skin.
谁派你来的
who sent you
你说你还有一个任务
you said you had another charge.
我知道我说了什么
i know what i said.
克拉克说贝拉米去侦察了
clarke said bellamy went to scout.
我来这里了
no one knew i was coming out here except for my people.
普莱姆们知道她是夜之血脉
the primes knew she was a nightblood.
天啊
oh, my god...
那不是克拉克
that's not clarke.
她是普莱姆  你在保护她
she's a prime, and you're protecting her.
我以我母亲的灵魂发誓
i swear on my mother's soul,
如果贝拉米死了
if bellamy is dead,
我就弄死你
i'll slit your master's throat.
他没死
he's not dead, ok
他还能活到第二月亮
he has until second moon.
谢谢你说实话
thank you for being truthful.
如果还来得及我就回来找你
i'll come back for you if i'm in time.
我不想要争斗
i don't want to fight, ok
你怎么来了
why are you here
因为我们都对目前的现状
because we're both struggling
不甚满意  我希望
to live with this, and i was hoping
我们彼此能够互相帮助走出困境
maybe we could help each other through it.
你去找了我父亲
you went to my father
- 我冒了很大的风险  - 嗯
- i take big swings. - hmm.
你在做什么
what are you doing
拯救我们
saving us.
他知道你杀了克拉克
he knows you killed clarke,
不像你背后那条毒蛇
and, unlike the snake behind you,
他会在那假慈悲
he will cry over spilled milk.
够了
enough.
你究竟是怎么了
what the hell's  the matter with you
变得如此麻木不仁
have you become so callous to the feelings
你难道不记得
of others that you don't remember
失去你所爱的人是什么样的感受了吗
what it's like to lose someone you love
我知道你很痛苦
I know you're in pain.
我知道你想要复仇   我也想要复仇
i know you want revenge. i would, too.
我们得到一个机会救回我们的女儿  我们就抓住了
we had a chance to bring back our daughter, and we took it.
我们没有考虑到后果
we didn't consider the consequences.
- 老天  - 安静
- for god's sake - be quiet.
也许你该让他说完
maybe you should just let the man speak.
- 闭嘴  墨菲  - 闭嘴  墨菲
- shut up, murphy. - shut up, murphy.
我想你应该听他说完
i think you should hear him out.
我想我们可以信任他
i think we can trust him.
- 你不知道  - 你可以  听着
- do you now - you can. look.
我没办法把你的朋友救回来
I can't bring your friend back,
但是我可以保证你们幸存下来人的安全
but i can guarantee safety for the rest of your people.
我们会将在这颗卫星上
we'll share everything we've learned
我们所学到的生存技巧传授给你们
about surviving on this moon.
我们的船怎么离开了
why did our ship just take off
艾比正在教他们如何制作夜血
abby's showing them how to make nightblood.
看来她还不知道她的女儿死了
i take it she doesn't know that her daughter is dead.
你也得把她处理掉
you're gonna have to kill her, too.
你觉得我复仇的欲望很强烈
you think my need for revenge is strong
这件事只有一种结局
there's only one way this ends.
贝拉米  停下
bellamy, stop, all right
你不会希望让他们把我们都杀死
you don't want them to kill all of us.
好好想想
just think.
乔瑟芬
josephine!
贝拉米  住手
bellamy, come on. don't do this.
对不起  爸爸  他们只知道暴力
i'm sorry, daddy. violence is all they know.
如果你要杀了他
if killing him is what you need,
那就动手吧  但是这种暴行的结局就是
then do it, but let the violence end here...
以眼还眼
and eye for an eye.
这叫冒险
big swings.
结果如何
so what's the verdict
症状的蔓延似乎停止了
the spreading seems to have slowed.
这是个好现象
that's a good thing, right
给你争取了一些时间
it's buying you some time.
我不明白
i don't understand.
这明明加快了我的痊愈速度  为什么对她不管用
it speed up my healing. why is it slowing hers
我猜是因为上了年纪就没办法再痊愈
i supposed it's because you don't heal old age,
但是说真的  我也不清楚
but the truth is, i have no idea.
我还有多长时间
how long do i have
不会很久了
not long,
约莫一两天
a day, maybe two.
你说你能够治好她的
you said it would cure her.
我说的是有可能
actually, i said it might.
切掉
cut it off.
- 你胆量不小  - 这样有用吗
- bold move. - will it work
你要是敢说可能有用你可就要有麻烦了
and if you say, "it might," we're gonna have a problem.
等一下  你手臂的运动方式
hold on.  your arm's movement.
我
i
我想要尝试一样东西
i want to try something.
来
here.
把石头抵在石块上
let it scrape against the boulder.
不要控制你手的移动
don't try to control your hand.
让它自己移动  闭上你的眼睛
just let it move. close your eyes.
可以了  睁开眼看看
that's enough. take a look.
这是对数螺旋线
a logarithmic spiral,
和异常现象的图案一致
the shape of the anomaly.
那里是瞬时风暴的源头
it's the source of  the temporal flares.
我不明白  这意味着什么
i don't understand. what does it mean
这不是简单的手抖
it's not just a tremor.
这是一条信息
it's a message.
异象在召唤你
the anomaly's calling you...
就像它曾经召唤我那样
just like it called me.
异象想要什么
i guess we better see what the hell this anomaly wants.
贝拉米
bellamy...
怎么了
what's going on
克拉克死了
clarke's dead.
我们什么时候发动袭击
so when do we attack
我们不袭击
we don't.
我们按照克拉克生前的意愿
we do what clarke would have done.
我们生存下去
we survive.
麦蒂
madi, hey...
我要告诉你件事
i have something to tell you.
很抱歉你失去了亲人
i'm so sorry,
但是训练会帮你度过这段难过的时光
but training will help you get through this.
指挥官
heda
这是你的错
this is your fault.
- 我能理解你很难过  - 难过
- i know you're upset. - "upset"
他们杀害了她
they killed her,
现在贝拉米告诉我  我们不能复仇
and now bellamy says we can't get revenge.
我能理解你想要复仇的心情
i understand why  you might want that,
但是如果复仇会招致战争
but if revenge leads to war--
别再说教了
no more lessons.
动手
指挥官  我们可以一起度过难关
heda, we can get through this together.
杀了她  只有这样你才能够复仇
不
no.
我作为指挥官在此将你驱逐
as your commander, you are hereby banished.
指挥官  你再考虑一下
heda, think.
你的命令我不敢不从
i'll have no choice but to obey your command,
但你现在需要我的帮助
and you need my help now.
我让你走
i said go...
立刻马上
now...
否则你只有死路一条
before i kill you.
你心软了
作为统领绝不应该
闭嘴
shut up.
告诉我该怎么将他们斩尽杀绝
今天 很好  明天 会更好
[鈾?I 鈾?
[鈾?Don't belong 鈾?
[鈾?Slowly slip back inside of my mind 鈾?
*我*
*i *
妈妈
mom
我害怕
i'm scared.
克拉克
clarke...
我害怕
i'm afraid.
你没必要一个人这么做
you don't have to do this without...
我不会让你死于这场纷争
i will not let you die in this war.
我们能谈点别的吗
can we talk about something else
我们不必再谈了
we don't have to talk at all.
■
人人视频APP
美剧、韩剧、日剧
离线高清缓存
支持电视投屏
各大应用商店均可下载
在线看美剧的追剧神器
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177